Preliminary Inventory to the Joseph Stancliffe Davis Papers, 1918-1972
Hoover Institution Archives
Joseph Stancliffe Davis Papers,
1918-1972
41001
Davis, Joseph Stancliffe, 1885-
7 manuscript boxes (2.9 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Writings, reports, memoranda, correspondence, and printed matter, relating to American agricultural policy during the presidential administration of Herbert Hoover, the Federal Farm Board, economic conditions in Europe, and the Dawes Commission on German reparations.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
Dawes, Charles Gates, 1865-1951.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Allied Maritime Transport Council (1918-1919); Inter-Allied Commission for Reparations.; United States. Federal Farm Board.; Agriculture--United States.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Reparations.; Europe.; Europe--Economic conditions--1918-1945.; Germany.; Germany--Economic conditions--1918-1945.; United States--Politics and government.; United States--Foreign relations.; Economists.
Container List
- Two (2) indexes of the Federal Farm Board Press Releases. (Box 1)
- News Digest (1933-incomplete) issued by the Agricultural Adjustment Administration.
- Farm Credit Administration Press Releases (November 1933).
- Department of Agriculture, Weekly News Service Releases, 1933.
- Federal Farm Board Press Releases (1929).
- Federal Farm Board Press Releases (1930). (Box 2)
- Federal Farm Board Press Releases (1931-1933). (Box 3)
- Wheat, Canada (Box 4)
- Wheat, China
- Wheat, Danube
- Wheat, Europe
- Wheat, Germany
- Wheat, India
- Wheat, Russia
- Wheat, Campaign
- Wheat, Exports and Shipments
- Wheat, Foreign Tariffs, etc.
- Wheat, Future Trading
- Wheat, Import - Requirements
- Wheat, International Conference
- Wheat, Milling
- Wheat, Outlook
- Wheat, Plans
- Wheat, Pure Analysis
- Wheat, Prices
- Wheat, Production
- Wheat, Readjustments
- Wheat, Relief
- Wheat, Speculation
- Wheat, Stabilization Operations
- Wheat, Stabilization
- Wheat, Storage
- Wheat, Visibles
- Business situation (1930-1931) (Box 5)
- European economic situation (1930-1931)
- Federal Farm Board, economic conditions (Gt. Brit., Australia, 1930-1931)
- Economist's conference, May 18-19, 1931.
- Foreign Service (1930-1931)
- Cotton co-op. policy (annual report material)
- Corn
- Grapefruit
- Millfeed
- Rice
- Wool
- Various commodities
- Cotton Policy
- Federal Farm Board, Economics Division memo (unclassified), (August 1931 and October 1931)
- Cotton Statement
- Federal Farm Board - Wheat Statements
- Hoover War Library
- Davis, Joseph S.
  - Personal data
  - Trip to London, 1918-1919 (Shipping Mission)
  - London correspondence, 1918-1919
  - Notes on Allied Maritime Transport Council experience, 1919
- Drafts to pt.1, chapter 3 European and International Developments, 1919-29, of The World Between the Wars, 1919-39 (1975), by Joseph S. Davis, p. 44-81 (Box 6)
- International Debts in Retrospect and Prospect, by J.S. Davis (Institute of Politics, 1927)
- The Next 100 Years of the American Statistical Association. (Reprint from the Journal of the American Statistical Association, March 1940, vol. 35, pt. 2, p. 261-272)
- Reflections on Strengths; Deterioration, and Problems of University Departments, 1963
- The Work of the Dawes Committee. Lecture, 1924
- Report of Committees of Experts to Reparation Commission; Report of the First Committee of Experts. 1924
- Notes on Interviews in Europe from J.S. Davis.
- Correspondence
  - 1921-1926
- Correspondence (Box 7)
  - Raymond Henle, Director of the Herbert Hoover Oral History Program
  - Herbert Hoover
  - Hoover Papers & Comments (correspondence with H.M. Creech, E. Holman, H. Fisher, and others, re J. Davis' article Herbert Hoover, 1874-1964; another appraisal)
  - Sir Cyril Hurcomb
  - Sir Arthur Salter
- Miscellanea